Welcome.
This is part one of
a series of four videos
showing the current
geographic locations of
1,086,919 genetic variants
from chromosome 22.
This video covers
the period
from 2.2 million years ago
to 50,000 years ago.
The date on the
bottom is an estimate
of when the
genetic variant arose.
The red dots show where
a genetic variant
has been found in
a modern population.
The treble clef
(and the matching music)
indicates what the
DNA change was.
The squiggly line
around the outside
is the chromosome.
The orange dot shows
the variant's location
on the chromosome.
"Site" is the exact
location of the variant
on the chromosome.
"Count" shows where you
are in the video series.
Each population where a
genetic variant was found
is listed in
the small print.
These genetic variants
were collected by
the Simons Genome
Diversity Project
the Human Genome
and the 1000
Genomes Project.
Dates were estimated by
Wohns et al. in
"A unified genealogy of
modern and ancient genomes."
The world map is
Philippe Rivière's re-creation
of Bertin's 1953 projection.
The chromsome map
uses Jakub Červený's
generalized Hilbert
space-filling curve.
Enjoy.