Welcome.
This is part 4 of
a 5-part video series
mapping 1,030,937 genetic
variants from chromosome 22.
Part 4 covers variants from
10,000 to 1,000 years ago.
These genetic variants were
collected from 3,754 people
by the Simons Genome
Diversity Project,
the Human Genome
and the 1000
Genomes Project.
Dates when the variants
first appeared in humans
were estimated by
Wohns et al. in their paper
"A unified genealogy of
modern and ancient genomes."
The map shows where
the variants were found
in modern populations.
The video's border is a map
of the chromosome itself.
These estimates may change
as more data is collected
and analytical techniques
are refined.
Genetic variants found
in only one individual
or whose derived and
ancestral states were equal
have not been included
in this video,
and dates have
been rounded.
Many human groups are
not represented
so be aware of gaps
in the data.
Enjoy.