Kimura, M. (1968). Evolutionary rate at the molecular
level. Nature, 217(5129), 624-626.
Ohta, T. (1973). Slightly deleterious mutant substitutions
in evolution. Nature, 246(5428), 96-98.
Duret, L. (2008) Neutral theory: The null hypothesis
of molecular evolution. Nature Education 1(1):218
Yengo, L., Sidorenko, J., Kemper, K. E., Zheng, Z., Wood, A. R.,
Frayling, T. M., Hirschhorn, J., Yang, J., & Visscher, P. M.,
the GIANT Consortium. (2018).
Meta-analysis of genome-wide association studies for height
and body mass index in ~700000 individuals of European ancestry.
Human molecular genetics, 27(20), 3641-3649.
https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddy271
Sohail, M., Maier, R. M., Ganna, A., Bloemendal, A.,
Martin, A. R., Turchin, M. C., Chiang, C. W. K.,
Hirschhorn, J., Daly, M. J., et al. (2019).
Polygenic adaptation on height is overestimated due to
uncorrected stratification in genome-wide association studies.
Elife, 8, e39702.
https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.39702
Lee, J. J., Wedow, R., Okbay, A., et al. (2018).
Gene discovery and polygenic prediction from a
1.1-million-person GWAS of educational attainment.
Nature genetics, 50(8), 1112.
https://doi.org/10.1038/s41588-018-0147-3
Cheesman, R., Hunjan, A., Coleman, J. R., Ahmadzadeh, Y.,
Plomin, R., McAdams, T. A., Eley, T. C., & Breen, G. (2020).
Comparison of adopted and nonadopted individuals reveals
gene-environment interplay for education in the UK Biobank.
Psychological science, 31(5), 582-591.
https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797620904450
Border, R., Johnson, E. C., Evans, L. M., Smolen, A.,
Berley, N., Sullivan, P. F., & Keller, M. C. (2019).
No support for historical candidate gene or candidate
gene-by-interaction hypotheses for major depression
across multiple large samples.
American Journal of Psychiatry, 176(5), 376-387.
https://doi.org/10.1176/appi.ajp.2018.18070881
Johnson, E. C., Border, R., Melroy-Greif, W. E.,
de Leeuw, C. A., Ehringer, M. A., & Keller, M. C. (2017).
No evidence that schizophrenia candidate genes are more
associated with schizophrenia than noncandidate genes.
Biological psychiatry, 82(10), 702-708.
https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopsych.2017.06.033
1000 Genomes Project Consortium.
A global reference for human genetic variation.
Nature 526, 68-74 (2015).
https://doi.org/10.1038/nature15393
Bergström, A., McCarthy, S., Hui, R., Almarri, M. A.,
Ayub, Q., Danecek, P., Chen, Y., et al.
Insights into human genetic variation and population
history from 929 diverse genomes.
Science 367 (2020).
https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aay5012
Mallick, S., Li, H., Lipson, M. et al.
The Simons genome diversity project: 300 genomes
from 142 diverse populations.
Nature 538, 201 (2016).
https://doi.org/10.1038/nature18964
Anthony Wilder Wohns, Yan Wong, Ben Jeffery, Ali Akbari,
Swapan Mallick, Ron Pinhasi, Nick Patterson, David Reich,
Jerome Kelleher, and Gil McVean (2021)
A unified genealogy of modern and ancient genomes.
bioRxiv 2021.02.16.431497
https://doi.org/10.1101/2021.02.16.431497
Serre, D., & Pääbo, S. (2004).
Evidence for gradients of human genetic diversity within
and among continents.
Genome research, 14(9), 1679-1685.
https://doi.org/10.1101/gr.2529604
Šavrič, B., Patterson, T., & Jenny, B. (2015).
The Natural Earth II world map projection.
International Journal of Cartography, 1(2), 123-133.
https://doi.org/10.1080/23729333.2015.1093312
Bertin, J. (1967).
Sémiologie graphique
Paris, Mouton/Gauthier-Villars, 1967.
https://visionscarto.net/bertin-projection-1953