Welcome.
The first million years
of this video series
are pretty boring.
Really.  It's like this
for a long time.
This is a teaser for a
5 part, 42 hour video series
mapping 1,228,178 genetic
variants from chromosome 22.
The variants were collected
from 3,754 people
and their date of origin
was estimated by Wohns et al
by building family trees for
each snippet of chromosome,
79,969 trees in total
for chromosome 22.
Part 1 of the series covers
from 2 million years ago...
...to 75,000 years ago.
Part 2 of the series covers
from 75,000 years ago...
...to 25,000 years ago.
Part 3 of the series covers
from 25,000 years ago...
...to 10,000 years ago.
Part 4 of the series covers
from 10,000 years ago...
...to 1,000 years ago.
Part 5 of the series covers
the final 1,000 years.
Enjoy.