Welcome.
The first million years
of this video series
are pretty boring.
That's because most
human genetic variation
is pretty boring.
Almost every common
genetic variant
has a tiny effect,
or no effect at all.
It takes hundreds of common
variants added together
to explain a fraction of the
variance in complex traits
like height, weight, schooling,
or psychiatric diagnosis.
Each genetic variant by itself
makes a tiny contribution.
Since most common variants
have a tiny effect
they're free to spread
more-or-less randomly.
That's what we're mostly
looking at right now:
Genetic variants which
don't do much
but which have gotten
lucky again and again
and spread across
the entire globe.
Later in the video series
we'll see genetic variants
which haven't
been as lucky
or haven't had as
much time to spread.
This is part 1 of
a 5-part video series
mapping 703,579 genetic
variants from chromosome 22.
This part covers variants from
2 million to 100,000 years ago.
These genetic variants were
collected from 3,754 people
by the Human Genome
Diversity Project,
the Simons Genome
and the 1000
Genomes Project.
Dates when the variants
first appeared in humans
were estimated by
Wohns et al. in their paper
"A unified genealogy of
modern and ancient genomes."
The map shows where
the variants were found
in modern populations.
The video's border is a map
of the chromosome itself.
Date estimates may change
as more data is collected
and analytical techniques
are refined.
Genetic variants found
in only one individual
have not been included
in these videos,
and dates have
been rounded.
Many human groups are
not represented
so be aware of gaps
in the data.
Enjoy.